Nao...
なお…君
Good morning, Yuki.
おはよう　ユキ姉
Clydesdale Platoon has returned from its
recon mission to Mazuurek Landing Castle.
クライスデール小隊
マズゥールカ揚陸城の偵察から帰還してきました
Roger that.
了解　ウェルドック開け
Open well dock.
And we're all back home.
全機帰投完了っと
Warrant Officer Kaizuka.
界塚准尉
Yes?
はい
Come with me to the captain's quarters later.
あとで艦長室に来てくれ　呼ばれている
We've both been called for.
Me too?
私もですか
Yeah. Something to do with the Deucalion.
ああ　デューカリオン絡みだ
Looks like it'll be back on Earth.
戻ってくるらしい
地球にな
We will make landfall at Port Aden.
帰投地点はアデン港確定っす
Calculate our time of reentry and let me know.
大気圏再突入の時間を割り出し　報告してください
Roger.
了解
No time for ourselves, huh?
行ったり来たり
Guess the brass want to milk us for all we've got.
上もいいように使い倒す気だな　俺たちを
Don't you think they just
appreciate the Deucalion's power?
それだけデューカリオンの力が買われてるってことじゃないですか
If anything, I think they simply
don't know what to do with us.
扱いかねてるって雰囲気ですね　どちらかと言えば
Please check our resupply list.
補給物資のリスト　最終確認　お願いします
I already have.
それはさっき済ませました　送って構いません
Go ahead and send it out.
Yes, ma'am.
はい
全艦に告ぐ
All hands!
UTC1300時
At 1300 UTC, we will begin our reentry sequence as directed.
通達どおり　本艦は地球降下シークエンスに移行する
kimi no te ga hirogeta nani mo nai sora yo
Your hands spread out the vast and empty sky
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
rikutsu no umi dake no kai wo asobeba
when you played with what the sea of reason would give
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
hodoite wa koboreta tagai no namida
Our tears welled up and fell
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
kouka shita kotoba uso kimagure
Words, lies, and whim down from orbit
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
soul art
Soul art
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
rhythm kanadete
We play a song now
aizu wo ringu ni tsunagu
and connect the signs to a ring
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
katachi dake no system to
A system of pure shape
katami dake no majinai mo
A magic spell without power
形見だけの呪いも
toubounin no hajirai on
The sound of shy fugitives
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
souzou drive carryon iji na tire
Carry on imagining, don't give up
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
gokai aru doa ni zero ga nemurikaketa
We're running out of false doors
tokei daita hito to tenshi
Men and angels embrace the passage of time
時計抱いた人と天使
towa ni aku doorutachi
They are dolls who gave up on eternity,
永久に飽くドール達
mata onaji kaze ni mogaite
fighting against this recurring fever
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
Want some Calvados?
カルバドスだが
いえ　結構です
Thank you, but no.
そうか
Okay.
Can I ask why we're needed as the Deucalion's escorts?
で　デューカリオンの護衛というのは
It's just a temporary assignment
while it's being resupplied and repaired.
あくまで補給と整備の間の一時的なものだがね
The base to which you'll be posted isn't very far from here.
指定の基地が　ここからさほど離れていないということもある
まんざら無縁の船でもないだろう
Don't you have people you know aboard that ship?
I admit I don't fully understand why you requested to be reassigned from it.
乗艦する予定だったのを断ったようだが
無駄に古傷を思い出すんで　あの船にいると
Being on that ship only reopens old wounds.
I also understand your younger brother serves there.
弟さんも乗っているそうだね
I've heard impressive things about him.
ずいぶん活躍していると聞いているが
ええ　まあ
I guess...
On second thought, may I?
いただいても？
Of course.
もちろんだ
その後諸侯の動きはいかがですか
How did the nobles act after that?
They don't wish to openly express their disapproval.
表立って反発を示している者はいないと聞いています
ハークライトの見立てですが
Or so says Harklight.
Do you think so too?
スレインもそうお思いですか
いえ
No.
伯爵の喪が明けぬうちに異を唱えるのはさすがに不謹慎
They are simply hesitant to broach the subject of inheritance while the dead are still being mourned.
そう思って当面　黙っているだけに過ぎません
The situation will change before long.
ザーツバルム卿の死が
There is no doubt that the loss of Count Saazbaum is a heavy blow to Vers.
ヴァースにとって多大なる損失であることは　紛うことなき事実
私は　父である二代目皇帝ギルゼリアが　月で犯した過ちによる娘
I am the result of an indiscretion my father,
the second emperor Gillzeria, made on the moon.
父の犯したもう一つの罪　ヘブンズ・フォールによって
His second sin was Heaven's Fall,
which cost him his life
父は他界し　この月すらも割れた
even as the very moon was shattered.
ザーツバルム卿は　身寄りを失った私を見つけ
Count Saazbaum found me and swore his allegiance to me when I had nothing.
忠誠を尽くしてくれました
心の奥では何を考えていたかは分かりませんが
I don't know if he had any ulterior motives...
しかしそれで良いのです
but that is fine.
権謀術数巡らす器量もなき者は　かえって信じられません
I find it more difficult to trust someone without Machiavellian ambition.
I hope you're looking forward to shouldering the brunt of their envy, Slaine.
これからは　妬み嫉みを嫌でも買わざるを得ませんね　スレイン
ザーツバルム卿のすべての特権
All of Count Saazbaum's privileges are now yours,
アセイラム姫の後見という立場までも　あなたは受け継いだのですから
as well as guardianship of Princess Asseylum.
覚悟しております
Come what may, I am prepared.
I would not leave this duty to anyone else.
されども　妬まれるかいのある重責
That outfit looks good on you.
その服　とてもよく似合ってますよ
忘れないでくださいね
I hope you won't forget.
The princess you must protect right now is in front of you.
今あなたが守らねばならぬ姫は　目の前にいることを
I have never forgotten.
重々承知しております
どこの馬の骨とも分からぬ者に跡目を継がせた挙句
How ill-fated that he should die a sudden death immediately after naming some peasant as his heir.
非業の死を遂げるとは
ザーツバルム卿も運の悪い
Fortune did not favor Count Saazbaum.
Perhaps this was recompense for his folly.
酔狂の報いかもしれませぬな
He may have been caught off-guard.
存外寝首をかかれたのかも
Are you suggesting that he was betrayed by an ally?
裏切られたとでも言うのですか　ザーツバルム卿が
止せ　確たる証左がなければ流言としか聞こえん
That's enough.
Don't spread rumors like that without evidence.
Regardless, the honor of all us knights is at risk.
とにかく　騎士の品格にも関わる問題
He must be shown the limits of his reach.
これ以上奴をのさばらせておくわけにはいきません
マズゥールカ卿
Count Mazuurek,
we are aware that you try to avoid wanton destruction in order to seize Earth's resources.
貴公が地球資源の確保を優先とするがために
破壊的な侵略を極力避けていることは承知している
I have no intention to criticize that in and of itself.
いや　そのことを責めようというのではない
だが　今は地球侵攻を強引にでも推し進める時
However, I believe the time calls for a brutal offensive.
As things stand, the authority of the
Thirty-Seven Clans is only set to decline.
37家門と謳われし騎士団の威光もこのままでは陰りを増すのみ
勢力争いは脇に置いて
We need to cease our infighting and pool our resources.
これからは協力し合う派閥も必要
What say you, Count Mazuurek?
どう思われる　マズゥールカ卿
騎士たる者　牙剥く者を倒すのは凡庸
Any knight can simply slay those who defy him.
An exceptional knight proves himself so superior that none dare try.
牙剥かせぬほどに格差を見せつけることこそ肝心
Words of wisdom.
至言でございますな
ザーツバルムの言葉だ
They're Count Saazbaum's.
だからこそ　ここで念押しする必要がある
Which is why his peers must be reminded as such.
Condition: generally satisfactory.
概ね良好
気になる部分は特にないですね
Nothing I'm particularly concerned about.
そう言ってるだろ
I told you I'm fine.
So could you start cutting me some slack?
そろそろ自由にしてほしいもんだな
How's the war?
ところでどうです　戦況は
I would have expected fiercer fighting.
もっと一気呵成に来るんじゃないかって思ってました
After all, there's basically no hope for a peace treaty at this point.
和睦の可能性は限りなく低くなったわけですし
Mars isn't monolithic.
火星も一枚岩じゃない
Sure, some of them attack Earth
purely out of malice,
単純に地球憎しで攻撃してくる奴もいるだろうが
but others are more interested in our natural resources.
資源としての確保を優先したい者もいる
敢えて抑制してるということですか
Oh, so you're saying those ones would try to avoid needless destruction?
でも…
Although...
まさか　彼らも主力のカタフラクトが
Do you think it might be because they're surprised at losing so many of their front-line Cataphracts?
ああも次々倒されるとは夢にも思っていなかったんじゃないてずか
Things aren't going according to plan,
they feel stiff resistance,
思惑が外れて　脅威を感じ　警戒モードに入っている
and now they're backing off
to see what's going on.
Sure, maybe.
かもな
だが　そのきっかけを作ったのはたった一人の少年
But this respite is all thanks to one boy.
Inaho, you mean?
イナホ君　ですね
ユキさんも気が気じゃないでしょうね
I wonder if Yuki's feeling worried about him.
Probably.
軍から外したくて再三上に頼んでいたようだが
She kept petitioning the brass to have him withdrawn from the military, after all.
Isn't that just a rumor?
それ　ただの噂じゃないんですか
Along with how they got tired of her and assigned her here.
あまりしつこいから　疎んじられてここに配属されたって
Possible enemy sky carriers detected east and west of Yemen
イエメン南西　アデンより　北東14キロの砂漠地帯
and in the desert region roughly fourteen kilometers northeast of Aden.
敵スカイキャリアと思しき機影を捕捉
東6キロに市街地
There's a town six kilometers to the east.
Let's draw him away from there.
そちらに向かわせないよう足止めする
Hold your fire until he's in range.
各機射程距離で待機
Wait for my order.
命令とともに攻撃開始
了解
Roger.
攻撃
Open fire!
敵カタフラクト進行中
Enemy Cataphract advancing!
The rounds are hitting him!
攻撃は効いてる
Don't stop!
続けろ
What the hell's going on?
何なんだ
The rounds are...
銃弾が…
A tornado?
竜巻？
No.
いえ　風速　風量　気圧にも大きな変化が…
Wind speed, air flow,
and atmospheric pressure all within—
M-My head...
あ…頭が　締め付けられる
It's being... squashed...
Behold, Count Barouhcruz.
バルークルス卿
I fight in a manner befitting my title within the Orbital Knights.
軌道騎士の名と爵位に恥じぬ我が戦いぶり　とくとご覧あれ
ま…待て　クライスデール22
W-Wait, Clydesdale 22!
だ…大丈夫か
A-Are you okay?
Th-That was really close!
ど…どうにか
下がってろ
Fall back!
いったい　何が
Seriously, what the hell is going on?
Lieutenant, look at the gauges!
大尉　計器を
加速度計を　見てください
Check the accelerometer!
重力
Gravity...
やつが重力を操っているというのか
Is he manipulating gravity?
加速度計が異常な振幅を示しています
There are large oscillations on my accelerometer.
重力体と潮汐体の一対となって
They're acting as gravitational-tidal pairs
revolving at high speed around the Cataphract.
あの機体の周囲を高速で回転し
それによって…
He uses that to...
重力波？
To create gravitational waves?
ええ
Yes.
近づけば潮汐力の振動で物体はちぎられ
So anything that gets too close will be torn apart by the tidal forces,
and any attack will be deflected, huh?
攻撃は逸らされるってわけか
Is that what's causing the sound in our heads?
じゃ　頭に直接響くこの音も…
恐らくな
Most likely.
I bear the people of this world no ill will,
この星の民に恨みはないが
これもヴァースの未来のため
but I must do this for the future of Vers!
来るぞ
He's approaching!
We can't let him reach the city!
このままでは市街地にまでミスミスやつを
誘導し　引き離すんだ
Let's draw him away from it!
How?!
しかし　手段が
界塚
Kaizuka!
はい
Sir?
母艦に問い合わせてくれ
Call the ship.
上空に重力波を観測できる設備を持った
Ask them if there are any satellite bases above with equipment to detect gravity waves.
サテライトベースがないかどうかを
Don't you understand the futility of your efforts?
わからぬか　無駄な足掻きだというのが
It's no use!
む　無理です
The rounds are destroyed
before they can reach him!
届く前に　砕けて
They might not be damaging him,
but they're effective at keeping his attention!
ダメージは与えられなくてもやつを引きつける効果はある
We're now ten kilometers away from the town!
市街地からさらに１０キロ
The plan to draw him away is working!
確実に誘導はできてます
Two more kilometers.
後　南へ２キロ
そこまで　そこまでやつを誘導するんだ
That's all.
That's all we have to keep his attention for!
どうした　動きを止めるな
What're you doing?
Don't stop!
クライスデール２２　クライスデール３３
Clydesdale 22!
Clydesdale 33!
くっそ　界塚
Goddamnit.
Kaizuka.
I'll keep him busy.
やつを引きつける
二人を回収してくれ
You get them out of here.
Lieutenant?
大尉…
来やがれ　ツイスター野郎
I'm over here, you twister freak!
It is meaningless.
無意味だ
Why do you persist?
なぜそんなことをする　その行為に何の価値がある
What merit does it hold?
Lieutenant...
大尉
やベえな　近すぎる
This ain't good.
He's too close.
距離をとって　もう少し
Gotta distance myself...
just a little more...
Come on.
来い　来るんだ
It's coming.
Goddamnit!
くっそ
どう足掻いても逃げられないのか　この記憶から
No matter how hard I try,
I'll never be free of these scars, will I?
Thank you for luring it into position,
Lieutenant Marito.
誘導　ありがとうございます　鞠戸大尉
Laser transmission?
レーザー通信？
ユキ姉　しばらく
Yuki, one moment.
Nao?
なお君？
やつの重力波は水平方向に変動する波動
His gravity waves ripple outward from him horizontally.
垂直方向の重力波は積分されて影響がなくなる
The ones that move vertically are integrated and lose their effect.
誤差修正　コンマ2度パーセコンド　ロックオン
Compensating for error.
Point-two degrees per second.
Locked on.
撃て
Fire!
デューカリオンと連絡が取れたのが幸いだった
Good thing we managed to get through to the Deucalion.
Or rather...
いや　あいつがいたからか
Good thing that he was aboard.
Ten minutes till reentry!
大気圏突入１０分前
Mustang 00, inside, quickly.
マスタング００　回収急げ
We've moved out of range.
狙える空域を外れました
お手伝いできるのは　ここまでのようです
It looks like this is all the help we can give you.
いや　十分だ　界塚弟
That's all right.
I can take it from here, Kaizuka Junior.
TK-67 and 68 have entered guidance tracks.
TK６７　６８　誘導軌道に入りました
Gate opening.
ゲート　開放します
There's no end of trash to take out.
なかなか捗りませんね　ゴミ掃除
The amount of debris left after a huge battle like that is no joke.
あれだけの戦いだったからな
散らばったデブリの数も半端じゃない
参りますよ　シャトルの出入りが一苦労です
Well, it's terrible. Shuttles can hardly launch or dock now.
レーダーに感あり
Something's on radar!
No response to IFF!
敵味方識別信号　応答なし
Forgive me, sir. I didn't pick it up earlier because of all the debris!
申し訳ありません
デブリに紛れて接近してきたため　捕捉が遅れました
One unit, you say?
一機だけだと
たかが一機に何をてこずっている
What do they hope to do with one unit?
Well...
それが…
１０キロまで接近
Ten kilometers and closing!
Unbelievable.
信じられん　密集したデブリの中を　あの速度で
How can it fly through such dense debris at that speed?
カタフラクト隊　発進急げ
Launch Cataphract platoons on the double!
Long time no see, Yuki!
お久しぶりです　ユキさん
Seriously, you just left without saying goodbye!
もう　いきなりいなくなっちゃうですもん
We were scared!
びっくりしましたよ
Sorry. Adults have to do these things sometimes.
ごめんね　大人の事情ってやつでね
But we can fight together again now, right?
また一緒に戦えるんですよね
みんな　頑張ってるみたいね
Looks like you guys have been busy.
We have!
はい
I'm glad to see you're well, Yuki.
ユキさんも　お変りなく
Rayet!
ライエちゃん
How are you?
どう　居心地は
Fitting in?
悪くない
I'm all right.
良かった
That's good.
イナホも元気ですよ
Inaho's doing fine too.
Seems so.
そうみたいね
Have you guys talked already?
もう会ったんですか
声で挨拶しただけ
Just over the radio.
向こうはそれで十分だと思ってるのかもしれないけど
Sure, he might think that's enough...
そうですか　またあの記憶が
I see.
Those mental scars, huh?
It's like they're branded into my brain.
どうにも逃れられないように出来てるらしい
Could they have been brought back on purpose?
敢えて蘇ったものだとは考えられませんか
Huh?
薄れそうになる意識を支えるために
Shock therapy you administered to give a boost to your fading consciousness.
自らが選んだショック療法
バカな
No way.
あの悲劇の記憶を大尉は
It may be possible, Lieutenant, that you're using those tragic memories to give yourself a reason to fight.
もしかしたら自分が戦う理由にしているのかもしれません
無論　自覚的にではありませんが
Not on a conscious level, of course.
You're saying I've already overcome them?
克服したということなのか
At the very least, you've won the battle.
少なくともあなたは戦いに勝利した
I think it was here...
確か　この辺に
その事実だけは受け入れて構わないでしょう
I hope you accept that fact, if nothing else.
There!
あった
俺のだ
That's mine!
そんなとこに隠していたのか
That's where you were hiding it?
過去に向き合いつつあるなら
If you're facing your past now, surely your reason for drinking has changed as well.
酒を飲む意味だってきっと変わってくる
I hope you sterilized that glass.
おい　消毒してるんだろな　それ
大尉　大変です　トライデント基地は…
Lieutenant! Problem!
It's Trident Base!
襲撃時の録画っす
These are images from the attack.
シャトルがドッキングベイに入った所を狙われて
The moment the shuttles were inside the docking bay,
all their munitions were set off at once.
搭載した爆薬弾薬が一気に
最悪のタイミング
Talk about lousy timing.
No, I think it was planned.
いえ　狙ってきたのだと思います
狙って？
Planned?
派手に一戦混じえたばかりだし
It'd be easy to predict that shuttles would come directly after a large-scale battle.
シャトルが来ることは十分予想出来た
僕ら援軍が離れたことも多分確認済みでしょう
And they probably already checked
to make sure the reinforcements had left.
勝算があるから　一機で攻めてきたんです
The odds were in their favor,
so they sent just the one unit.
But the service details of munitions shuttles are supposed to be top secret.
でも　弾薬補給シャトルの運行状況はトップシークレットのはず
All they really do is change their service numbers and routes.
認識番号を変えたり補給経路を変えたり
やってることはそれぐらいです
You can crack those methods with cryptoanalysis and data sifting.
暗号解読と　データの払い出しを入念に行えば割り出せる
But...
しかし…
多分　それが出来る相手です
That's the kind of person we're dealing with.
スレイン様
Brilliant execution, Sir Slaine.
お見事です
何たるやつ…
The gall.
However, his results speak volumes.
結果に目をつぶるわけにはいかぬ
He accomplished his mission with flying colors.
やつは成すべきことを見事に果たし帰ってきた
None can call him a traitor now.
もはや裏切り者と誹ることも　これでは
Great causes seek the strong.
大義は常に強者に寄り添う
That mangy cur has draped himself in a wolf pelt.
忌々しき野良犬は　狼に姿を変えた
ハークライト　月に帰るぞ
Harklight.
We're returning to the moon.
タルシス
The Tharsis...
スレイン・トロイヤード
Slaine Troyard.
仕方ないか
Guess it's up to me.
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:ikiko&Archer   翻译:mam&郝郝
校对:安少&zwx   时间轴:Foyzi   压制:河蟹
僕たちは　彷徨える未来
bokutachi wa samayoeru mirai
We are a future of dubious likelihood
窮屈な空に　ヒカリを探している
kyuukutsu na sora ni
We look to the oppressive sky
hikari wo sagashiteiru
in search of light
furueru te wa muryoku de
Our trembling hands are powerless
震える手は無力で
叫びはまだ遠くて
sakebi wa mata tookute
Our screams reach no one
dakedo tobu koto wo
But we will never be afraid
たけど飛ぶことを恐れてはいられない
osorete wa irarenai
of flying
永遠じゃなくても　完璧じゃなくても
eien ja nakutemo
We don't need eternity
kanpeki ja nakutemo
We don't need perfection
背中合わせの世界を　真っ直ぐ生きてゆく
senaka-awase no sekai wo
We live in two related
massugu ikiteyuku
but wildly different worlds
nando kizu tsuitemo
No matter the wounds we receive
何度傷ついても　何度間違えても
nando machigaetemo
and the mistakes we make,
運命さえ飛び越えていこう
unmei sae tobikoete yukou
we will overcome fate
この宙の果てまで
kono sora no hate made
Until the skies above us end
創造を信じて
hajimari wo shinjite
we will believe in the genesis of a better life